SANTIYA GEORGIEVA

Frontend engineer

ABOUT ME

https://santiyageorgieva.onrender.com

Extremely motivated to constantly develop new skills, both soft and technical, and grow professionally. Passioned person with interests in cutting edge technologies. Possessing a broader perspective as a Front-end developer based on my current experience and achieved with self-study, perseverance and ambition. Active involvement in the open source community. Keep touch with the latest trends on Reddit, Medium, and so on.

GET IN TOUCH WITH ME

Sofia, Bulgaria +359 877 583 710 https://santiyageorgieva.onrender.com https://github.com/sgeorgieva santiyageorgieva@yahoo.com

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS AND TECHNOLOGIES

FNUIL	SSIUMAL SKILLS A	IND ILUINOLOU	ILJ
Front-end	Developer Tools	Version control	Project Management
 Reactjs 			tools
Redux	 VS Code 	• Git	
 NextJS 		 GitHub 	 Redmine
• ES2015/2016		 Gitlab 	 Assembla
 Twitter Bootstrap 		 Bitbucket 	Jira
 Material-UI 			
jQuery			
Angular 2+			

WORK EXPERIENCE

"Milky Bio Group" LTD. 09.2024- Present BILLER

"Teris" LTD. 05.2024- 06.2024 WEB DEVELOPER

Creative Idea Group / Pokrivala.net 10.2023 - 12.2023 WEB DEVELOPER

SummIT LTD. 09.2022 - 04.2023 FRONT-END DEVELOPER

myPos Technologies 03.2021 to 06.2022 WEB DEVELOPER

Prime Holding Jsc. 06.2019 to 02.2021 JUNIOR FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Prime Holding Jsc. 10.2018 to 06.2019 INTERN FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Prime Holding Jsc. 07.2018 to 09.2018

INTERSHIP TRAINEE AS FRONT-END DEVELOPER

OneCreative Media 07.2017 to 08.2017 and 07.2016 to 08.2016 STUDENT TRAINEE AS FRONT-END DEVELOPER

EDUCATION

2018 BSc(Hons) in Computer Systems Technology "Angel Kanchev" University, Ruse

2014

High School "Jordan Yovkov" Tutrakan, Silistra Province

SOFT SKILLS

- · Strong work ethic
- Empathic listener and persuasive speaker
- · Kind and helpful to others
- Enjoy working as a team members
- · well as independently
- Attention to details
- Fluent english (B2)

PROJECTS

CARD MANAGEMENT SYSTEM (CMS)

Technologies used: React, Redux, SCSS

Duration: 6 months

- · Creating reusable components
- Fixing major issues regarding product specifications
- · Refactoring components and styles based on new design changes
- Create new urgent components without design templates
- Make proposition of design changes for better user experience, readability
- Add new React libraries to achieve product specification

DISTRIBUTION AGENTS SYSTEM (DAS)

Technologies used: React, Redux, SCSS

Duration: 10 months

- · Creating reusable components
- Fixing major issues regarding product specifications
- · Refactoring components and styles based on new design changes
- Create new urgent components without design templates
- Make proposition of design changes for better user experience, readability
- Add new React libraries to achieve product specification

CLIENT/COMPANY: UNDER NDA

Technologies used: React, Redux, SCSS

Duration: 8 months

- · Creating reusable components
- · Fixing major issues regarding product specifications
- Refactoring components and styles based on new design changes
- Create new urgent components without design templates
- · Make proposition of design changes for better user experience, readability

COMPANY WEBSITE

Technologies used: jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS

Duration: 1 month

· Fixing major issues regard specifications

JIGSAW INTERACTIVE

Technologies used: Angular 8+, Telerik DevCraft/Kendo UI, SCSS, DevOps (Docker, Docker Compose)

Duration: 9 months

- Making a huge reskin (refactoring code) of a major fuctionallity
- Assisting to the team when creating the mobile version of the system
- · Being a part of a sustaining (cross-functional) team for fixing major bugs, regressions,
- etc. and handling high priority tasks in production
- Making propositions for better implementation of functionalities to the clients, if needed
- Helping to the teammates with their tasks or problems related to the project
- configurations
- Being a part of large front-end team

HR SOLUTION

Technologies used: ¡Query, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS

Duration: 2 months

 Assisting of the front-end team to make a reskin (refactoring code) of the system regard the styles and functionality

OVATIO

Technologies used: Wordpress

Duration: 1 month

- Creating a few templates using the embedded plugin (already installed and used) from the client for the website of the company
- Fixing issues regarding the styles
- Making a tutorial/guideline for the clients to change the content of the website after the described above changes

COMPANY WEBSITE

Technologies used: React, Redux, JavaScript, CSS Transitions, SCSS

Duration: 3 months

- Assisting with the front-end development for the reskin of the system
- Developing own components (not using predefined from Bootstrap/Material Design)
- Refactoring the business logic of the components to follow the best practices
- · Creating Javascript and CSS Transitions

TRAINING

- Side project veko-oil.eu
- Project pokrivalanet.onrender.com
- Portfolio santiyageorgieva.onrender.com
- Diploma project
- Course project created during my university education
- · B2 certificate from Info Bulgaria
- Educational Center
- UI Design Figma course
- Adobe Photoshop Basics Course
- Adobe Photoshop Advanced Course

VPN MANAGEMENT PLATFORM

Technologies used: React, Redux, JavaScript, Material UI, SCSS

Duration: 7 months

- · Fixing a major bugs in production mode
- Integrating REST API Services
- Improving the responsive design of the app
- Using Material UI for React
- Finding BE gaps
- · Helping managing the tasks for the team

OPPORTUNITY TRACKER

Technologies used: Angular 6, Angular Admin Template \cdot CoreUI for Angular

Duration: 2 months

- Using reusable components
- · Using the Admin template for Angular
- Integrating REST API Services
- · Improving the security of the FE part
- Finding BE gaps

CLIENT/COMPANY: UNDER NDA

Technologies used: Angular 6, HTML & Bootstrap Website Templates Colorlib Duration: 1 month

- · Seperate the templates to pices, so they can be used as own independent components
- Integrating REST API Services

VIG GROUP LTD.TRANSPORT & DISTRIBUTION COMPANY

Technologies used: Javascript, PHP Mailer, Twitter Bootstrap Duration: 2 months

- Creating a simple design of the project UI/UX.
- Developing the responsive website
- · Using the PHP mailer for the contact form
- · Integrating Google Maps API Services

PERSONAL PROJECTS

CLIENT/COMPANY: SANTIYA GEORGIEVA PROJECT NAME: PORTFOLIO

Technologies used: NextJS, React, Twitter Bootstrap, SCSS

Duration: 5 days

- Learning new technology
- · Developing dynamic components
- Create CSS3 Transitions

CLIENT/COMPANY: NONE (OPEN SOURCE) PROJECT NAME: HEALTHY BENEFITS

Technologies used: React, Redux, Javascript, Twitter Bootstrap

- Duration: 8 months
 Reworking the front-end part to achieve a better performance app which follows the latest
- cutting edge technologiesDeveloping dynamic components
- Learning new technologies in order to create, extend and improve the fuctionallity of existing project

CLIENT/COMPANY: NONE (OPEN SOURCE) PROJECT NAME: HEALTHY BENEFITS

Technologies used: Symphony, Twig, Twitter Bootstrap Duration: 2 months

- Developing a high dynimicly web-based system with MVC architecture
- Inventing the UX/UI design to provides a modern web app for the end users
- Implementing the responsive design
- Writing an excellent documentation for the project

CLIENT/COMPANY: NONE (OPEN SOURCE) PROJECT NAME: HEALTHY BENEFITS

Technologies used: Javascript, Twitter Bootstrap Duration: 3 months

- Represents a web-based system of the electronic reference book of RU "Angel Kanchev"
- The responsibilities within the project: front-end development and co-working
- with the rest of the team (UI designer, QA).